mirunapopa

data scientist



summary

Experienced in startup scenes, working closely with management in the company, eager to bring data closer to the rest of the company and to nourish a data driven mentality. Seeking challenging environments with creative and curious people, a place from which one never stops learning.

about

Zehdenicker Str. 15 10119 Berlin Deutschland

24 years old ■ miruna.c.popa @gmail.com □ +4917656977157

nirunapopa in mirunapopa

languages

romanian (native) english (fluent) german (beginner) spanish & french notions

programming

Python, Spark Scala, PostgreSQL Google Spreadsheets, Command Line, Redshift Fiddled with: SAS, Systat, HTML, CSS, Latex

graphic design

Fiddled with Adobe Suite (Illustrator, Indesign, Photoshop)

education

2011-2014 B.S. in Economic Cybernetics,

Statistics and Informatics Academy of Economic Studies, Bucharest, Romania Final Thesis: Music Recommendation Web App using Collaborative Filtering Algorithm and Scala Programming Language

2013-2014 Erasmus Student in

Computer Science

and Economics West Pomeranian University of Technology, Szczecin, Poland Topics Studied: Data Analysis & Machine Learning, Java Programming, Economic Analysis

experience

2014 - Present EyeEm GmbH, Berlin

- · handling internal requests, as well as improving the process
- providing data for both internal requests, as well as Board Presentations
- · automating recurring reports
- preparing ETL jobs which would feed data to Chartio Dashboards
- created a slack bot which would answer some frequently asked questions

07-10 2013 Softgames GmbH, Berlin

Internship QA

Data Analyst

- testing games on Java, Android, iOS, Blackberry
- · developing ad campaigns based on KPIs
- · new user funnel analysis
- working closely with product managers and external partners on the development of games

02-04 2013 Visionware Romania, Bucharest

Practicing Student

- · participated in trainings on .Net, SharePoint, Dynamics CRM
- · offered some practical solutions to existing problems

10-12 2012 Sanoma Hearst, Bucharest

Internship Marketing

- · created presentations and e-banners for Esquire, FHM
- · participated in promotional concepts for advertising campaigns

volunteering

2011-2013 Volunteers for Ideas and Projects, Bucharest

- Marketing & Sales Officer
- Art Direction Coordinator
- Organizer for Visual Playground, a graphical design school for students.

2007-2011 AntiDrug Consilium, Bacau

- Project Coordinator for around 10 projects
- awarded Volunteer of the Year in 2009

2007-2010 Ingenious Drama Festival, Bacau

- Chief of Magazine Department
- awarded Most active member of the Department